lenovo.com 2015-12-23

# Lenovo Privacy Policy

This privacy policy was last updated on 11/20/15

### About This Policy

Your privacy is important to Lenovo. This privacy policy applies to Lenovo's websites owned and operated by Lenovo. This statement discloses the information practices for Lenovo websites, including what type of information is collected and tracked, how the information is used, with whom the information is shared, and how the information is protected.

We reserve the right to make changes to this privacy statement at any time. If we make a change to this privacy policy, we will make previous versions available upon request so that you can see when changes occurred and what they are.

### TRUSTe's Program Compliance

Lenovo has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with TRUSTe's program requirements including transparency, accountability, and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. The TRUSTe program does not cover information that may be collected through downloadable software. The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through the following Lenovo sites: http://blog.lenovo.com, http://www.lenovo.com, http://www.lenovocareers.com. This program does not cover information that may be collected through our mobile applications. TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at [ privacy@lenovo.com](mailto:privacy@lenovo.com). If you are not satisfied with our response you can directly contact [TRUSTe](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request "TRUSTe Watchdog Program").

### How Lenovo Collects Personal Information

In general, you can visit Lenovo's websites without telling us who you are and without giving any personal information about yourself. There are times, however, when we or our partners may need information from you.

You may choose to give us personal information in a variety of situations. For example, you may want to give us information, such as your name and address or email id, to correspond with you, to process an order, or to provide you with a subscription. You may give us your credit card details to buy something from us or a description of your education and work experience in connection with a job opening at Lenovo that you want to be considered for. We intend to let you know how we will use such information before we collect it from you; if you tell us that you do not want us to use this information to make further contact with you beyond fulfilling your requests, we will respect your preference. If you give us personal information about somebody else, such as a spouse or work colleague, we will assume that you have their permission to do so. This information is only used for the sole purpose of completing your request or for whatever reason it may have been provided.

If you want to subscribe to marketing materials from Lenovo, we will use your name and email address. You may choose to stop receiving our marketing emails by following the unsubscribe instructions included in these emails, accessing the email preferences in your account settings page, or you can contact us at [ privacy@lenovo.com](mailto:privacy@lenovo.com).

### How Lenovo Uses & Shares Personal Information

The following paragraphs describe in more detail how Lenovo may use your personal information and with whom we may share it. Depending on the type of Lenovo website you are visiting, one or more of the paragraphs may apply. For example, if you order a product from a Lenovo website, your information will be handled as described in such paragraphs as Fulfilling Your Transaction Request and Marketing Use.

We will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy policy. We do not sell your personal information to third parties.

### When You Request a Transaction

If you request something from a Lenovo website, for example, a product or service, a callback, or specific marketing materials, we will use the information you provide to fulfill your request. To help us do this, we may share information with others, for instance, other parts of Lenovo, Lenovo's Business Partners, financial institutions, shipping companies, postal or government authorities (e.g., Customs authorities) involved in fulfillment. In connection with a transaction we may also contact you as part of our customer satisfaction surveys or for market research purposes.

### Mobile Messaging 

You can sign up to receive communications about our products and services via a mobile device. If you use this option, we may send you communications by text message or call. You can opt out of receiving these communications by texting “STOP” to 557755 or calling (866) 723-7954 to notify us to remove you. Standard text rates for your individual cellular contract may apply. We are not responsible for costs imposed by your carrier.   

### Marketing Uses

The information you provide to Lenovo on certain Lenovo websites may also be used by Lenovo and selected third parties for marketing purposes. Before we use it, however, we will offer you the opportunity to choose whether or not to have your information used in this way.

### Service Quality Monitoring

Certain website transactions may also involve you calling Lenovo or Lenovo calling you. Please note that, in some cases, we may record such calls for staff training and quality assurance purposes.

### Information for Business Partners

If you represent a Lenovo Business Partner, you may visit a Lenovo website intended specifically for Lenovo Business Partners. We may use information provided on that site to administer and develop our business relationship with you, the Business Partner you represent, and Lenovo Business Partners generally. For instance, this may involve using your information to send you details of Lenovo Business Partner programs. It may also include sharing certain information with other Business Partners (subject to any confidentiality obligations that may exist), or Lenovo customers or prospects. In connection with a particular transaction or program, we may also contact you as part of customer satisfaction surveys or for market research purposes.

### Lenovo Supplier Administration

If you represent a Lenovo supplier, you may visit a Lenovo website intended specifically for use by Lenovo suppliers. We may use the information provided on that site in connection with entering into or performing a transaction with you. For example, this may include sharing information with other parts of Lenovo, Lenovo's Business Partners, customers, shipping companies, financial institutions, postal or government authorities involved in fulfillment. It may also be used to administer and develop our relationship with you, the supplier you represent and/or other Lenovo suppliers generally.

### Disclosures Required by Law

Please be aware that, in certain circumstances, it's possible that personal information may be subject to judicial or other government subpoenas, warrants, or orders. Therefore, when we believe in good faith that the law requires it, we may disclose personal information to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request.

### Lenovo Blogs, Discussion Forums, & Chat Rooms

If you participate in a Lenovo blog, discussion forum, or chat room, you should be aware that the information you provide there may be made broadly available to others, potentially inside or outside Lenovo, who have access to that blog, discussion forum, or chat room. Also, please recognize that individual blogs, forums, and chat rooms may be hosted by organizations other than Lenovo and/or may have additional rules and conditions. Each participant's opinion on a blog, forum or chat room is his or her own and should not be considered as reflecting the opinion of Lenovo.

### Other Lenovo Website Notices & Worldwide Practices

In some cases, specific Lenovo websites may contain other notices about their use and the information practices applicable to those sites.

Lenovo is a global organization, with legal entities, business processes, management structures, and technical systems that cross borders. Our privacy practices are designed to provide protection for your personal information, all over the world.

We may share your personal information within Lenovo and transfer it to countries in the world where we do business.

Please note that some countries have privacy laws that are not equivalent to privacy laws in your own country. In such countries, Lenovo will still handle information in the manner we describe here.

### Protecting the Security & Integrity of Personal Information

Lenovo implements appropriate measures and processes to protect your personal information and to maintain its quality both during transmission and once it is received. For example, we use encryption when transmitting sensitive information such as a credit card number to help us to keep your information secure. If you have any questions about the security of your personal information, you can contact us at [ privacy@lenovo.com](mailto:privacy@lenovo.com).

### Supplementing Information

From time-to-time, we may supplement information you give us via a Lenovo website with information from other sources, such as information validating your address or other available information about businesses. This is to help us maintain the accuracy of the information we collect and to help us provide a better service.

### Use of Suppliers

In some cases, Lenovo uses suppliers to collect, use, analyze, and otherwise process information on its behalf. It is Lenovo practice to require such suppliers to handle information in a manner consistent with Lenovo policies.

### Information Retention

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you with services. We will also retain your information as necessary to comply with applicable legal obligations, to resolve disputes, and to enforce our agreements.

### Mergers & Acquisitions

Circumstances may arise when, whether for strategic or other business reasons, Lenovo decides to sell, buy, merge, or otherwise reorganize businesses in some countries, and you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our website of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information. Such a transaction may involve the disclosure of personal information to prospective or actual purchasers, or receiving it from sellers. It is Lenovo practice to seek appropriate protection for information in these types of transactions.

### Lenovo's Use of Cookies, Web Beacons, & Related Technologies

As is true of most websites, we collect certain information automatically and store it in log files. We sometimes collect non-identifiable information from visits to our websites to help us provide better customer service. For example, we keep track of the domains from which people visit, and we also measure visitor activity on Lenovo websites, but we do so in ways that keep the information non-identifiable. This information is sometimes known as "clickstream data." Lenovo or others on Lenovo’s behalf may use this data to analyze trends and statistics and to help us provide better customer service.

Also, when we collect personal information from you in a transaction, we may extract some information about that transaction in a non-identifiable format and combine it with other non-identifiable information such as clickstream data. This information is used and analyzed only at an aggregate level to help us understand trends and patterns. This information is not reviewed at an individual level. If you do not want your transaction details used in this manner you can disable your cookies.

We collect the information we mentioned in the previous paragraphs through the use of various technologies, including one called "cookies.” A cookie is a piece of data that a website can send to your browser, which may then be stored on your computer as an anonymous tag that identifies your computer but not you. Some Lenovo pages use cookies, sent by Lenovo or its third-party vendors, or other technologies such as java scripts and etags to better serve you when you return to the website. All browsers have settings that allow you to turn off cookies altogether, or alert you when a site wants to save one; keep in mind that turning off cookies can limit your access to certain parts of some sites.

Some Lenovo websites also use web beacon or other technologies such as java scripts and etags to better tailor those sites to provide better customer service. These technologies may be in use on a number of pages across Lenovo websites. When a visitor accesses these pages, a non-identifiable notice of that visit is generated, which may be processed by us or by our suppliers. These web beacons usually work in conjunction with cookies. If you turn off cookies, web beacons and other technologies will still detect visits to these pages, but the notices they generate cannot be associated with other non-identifiable cookie information and are disregarded.

Additionally, we use local storage objects (LSOs) such as HTML5 to store content information and preferences. Third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features on our site or to display advertising based upon your web browsing activity also use LSOs such as HTML 5 to collect and store information. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5 LSOs.

### Online Advertising

We may partner with a third party to either display advertising on our websites or to manage our advertising on other (non-Lenovo) sites. We or our third-party partners may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your website activities to provide you advertising based upon your interests. If you don't want to have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may [opt-out](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp "Advertising Opt Out"). You will still continue to receive generic ads.

### Personalized URL Link

On occasion, we may personalize and customize websites for certain visitors. If you visit one of these sites, you may find it customized with references to products and/or services that we believe may be of interest to you, based on your previous interactions with Lenovo and information you have provided to us. While you are visiting these websites, we may collect information about your visit to better tailor the site to your interests. An invitation to visit one of these websites can be presented as a personalized URL in an email, a notice on a website registration page, or as a response to you logging on to a certain website.

If you choose to visit one of these websites, you are agreeing to let Lenovo collect information about your visits and also to its association with other information about you and your relationship with Lenovo. If you do not want your information to be used in this way, do not accept the invitation to visit these sites.

### Children's Privacy

Lenovo's websites are intended for adults and children ages 13 and up who have permission to use them from their parents or legal guardians. We don't seek to collect information about children under the age of 13 and will delete any as soon as we discover it. We also encourage parents to actively supervise their children's use of the internet.

### Privacy Technology

Technology will increasingly help give you more control over your personal data. For useful resources and an overview of privacy-related tools, visit the [Privacy Alliance](http://www.privacyalliance.org/resources/rulesntools/ "Privacy Alliance Rules and Tools") site. Note that Lenovo has not formally evaluated these tools.

### Links to Non-Lenovo Websites

Lenovo websites may contain links to other websites. Lenovo is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of those other websites.

### Testimonials

Lenovo sometimes displays personal testimonials and other endorsements of satisfied customers on our site. With your consent we may post your testimonial along with your name. If you want to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at [ privacy@lenovo.com](mailto:privacy@lenovo.com).

### Social Media Features & Widgets

Our website includes social media features and links, such as the social bar with icons that link to the Lenovo presence on that specific site (e.g., the Lenovo page on Facebook, the Lenovo feed on Twitter). These features may collect your IP address and info on which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our site. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

### Frames & "Powered-By" Sites

Some of our pages use framing techniques to serve content from our partners while preserving the look and feel of our site. In addition, certain Lenovo-branded websites may be operated by third parties and may be designated by a "powered-by" logo. Please be aware that such sites may be governed by the privacy practices and policies of our partners and not necessarily those of Lenovo or Lenovo.com.

### Contacting Lenovo Privacy Program

If you have a question about this statement, you can contact Lenovo through the Privacy Submission Form or via US postal mail to Lenovo 1009 Think Place, Morrisville, North Carolina, USA 27560.

If you want to obtain a copy of particular information you provided to Lenovo, or if you become aware the information is incorrect and you would like us to correct it, or you want to request deletion of your personal information, contact us at [ privacy@lenovo.com](mailto:privacy@lenovo.com).

Before Lenovo is able to provide you with any information or correct any inaccuracies, however, we may ask you to verify your identity and to provide other details to help us to respond to your request. We will endeavor to respond within an appropriate timeframe.

This website is maintained by Lenovo or one of its subsidiaries around the world.
